Hello

I am Jon Kao

Johnakao@gmail.com

(678)793-1214

Summary

I am a neurophysiologist on a mission to help people live longer, healthier and happier lives. After eight years serving patients, I seek to step away from my clinical duties and find a lifelong career working alongside other inspired and passionate people in creating, designing, and implementing the technologies that will enhance our capabilities to reach even more people across the world.

Experience

Unaffiliated. San Francisco - *Coder*

August 2019 - Present Day

- Launched a Twitch brand with 500+ unique views and counting.
- Built personal and small business websites and a responsive blog theme.
- Built a company database with SQL based on characters from the popular television series, The Office.
- Built several titles out of Godot/GDScript and Unity/C#.
- Enrolled in Rithm School for Javascript/Web Development.

SpecialtyCare, San Francisco - Surgical Neurophysiologist

August 2016 - August 2019

- Learned to perform clinical duties with considerations for ethics and compassion from mentors along the San Francisco Bay Area regions including esteemed neurosurgeon, author and friend, Dr. James Doty.
- Drive cross functional strategy and management of diverse healthcare products including perfusion, sterile
 processing, neurophysiological monitoring, and surgical support providing for more than 14,000 physicians
 nationwide.
- Reduction of the national occurrence of intraoperative complications through stringent practices of live data recording, analysis, and reporting in 95% of relevant neurosurgical procedures in urban teaching hospitals nationwide.
- Facilitate international recognition of practices as standard of care and growth of neuromonitoring products consumption by hospitals by 300% over the past decade.
- Work closely with diverse healthcare professionals including managers, anesthesiologists, pathologists, surgeons, and nurses to lead execution of surgical procedures aimed to achieve excellent patient care results for over 400,000 patients.
- Work within diverse surgical teams to ensure patient care outcomes in dynamic situations with a focus on clear and concise communication and prioritization of life preservation.
- Creating and implementing programs and mechanisms for reducing technical and anesthetic confounds to <0.15% of cases.

- Create and design safer neurosurgical processes/programs using aggregate patient data sets including;
 - Pre-operative risk level assessments and identification of contraindications.
 - Pre-operative planning and approaches formulated and presented within the surgical team as well as with the patient families.
 - Contingency and adaptive planning with implementation protocols in events of complications.
 - Sterile handling processes in the operating room aimed to dramatically combat contamination risks, reducing overall surgical times and infection rates increasing patient post-operative survivability by up to 98%.
 - Utilization of feedback loops within multiple steps of the neurosurgical process to reduce incidences from miscommunication to less than 1% of cases yearly.
 - Post-op examinations and clinical correlation examinations for confirmation of validity of neurosurgical reports and data collections.
 - o Implementation of electrophysiological instruments at disposal such as electroencephalography to reduce anesthetic wastes/confounds.
 - Utilization of clinical time by implementation of single minute change of die and codifying hand-off procedures to minimize downtime and ensure continuity of care.
- Serve as the external and internal point of contact for key partners within national territories resolving physician/patient issues while maintaining partner relationships leading to reduced attrition rates of greater than 85%.
- Creating collaborative teamwork environments by meetings with key partners and reviewing data sets and interesting case studies to explore potential avenues and applications of neurosurgical products leading to annual sales volume increases of over 5%.
- Training of diverse clinicians in industry standards and company practices driving team growths along the West Coast territories to record highs.

Neuropath, Atlanta - Surgical Neurophysiologist

August 2013 - August 2016

- Learned complex cranial and spinal electrophysiological techniques from mentors in the Greater Atlanta Metropolitan Area including Dr. Sanjay Gupta, chief of neurosurgery at Grady and medical reporter at CNN.
- Managed multiple accounts across several facilities and our partners within and without hospital systems to drive case volumes 1.5x baseline.
- Attended international conferences to study global industry medical techniques and expand corporate brands.
- Worked closely with cross functional teams to lead execution of neurosurgical support for internal and external partners.
- Served as the point of contact for key partners to independently resolve issues, review key metrics, and feedback to management for reiteration.
- Build and manage relationships between new surgical contracts and verticals including neurophysiology, sterile processing, perfusion, and other services by:
 - Staying on top of each stakeholder's current and upcoming campaigns, promotions, and priorities.

- Maintaining a learnings library to ensure campaigns are optimized over previous ones, continuously meeting or beating benchmarks.
- Work hand in hand with partner alliances team as well as directly with other providers to develop full product lifecycle campaigns for hospitals and surgeons.

Education

Kennesaw State University, College of Science and Mathematics *B.S. in Chemistry 2013;* Graduated Dean's List

Lean Six Sigma Certification

ABRET - *CNIM* #3032

Rithm School

2020 - Present

Skills

Spanish | Chinese | Microsoft Office | Medical Reporting | HTML & CSS | SQL | Javascript

Interests

Boxing | Guitar | Gaming | Food & Travel | Business | Reading | Investment | Technology | Healthcare